(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T23:26:59.138093",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
しゅっぱーつ！
Here we go!
ホロライブ2期生 大空スバル！
Hololive 2nd Generation, Oozora Subaru!
今日はみんな楽しんでってね！
Everyone, make sure to have fun today!
ちょこっとヤンチャで
A little mischievous,
ニコっと元気な
with a cheerful smile,
キラッとスマイル
and a sparkling smile...
アイドル
Idol!
毎日をもっと楽しくしたいとよ
I want to make every day more fun!
with アドベンチャー
with adventure!
ひらひらスカートも
Even with a fluttering skirt,
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear it perfectly!
だからもっともっと 好きになってもいいよ
So it's okay to love me more and more!
一緒に
Together...
大空に飛び立とう
let's fly high into the sky!
光れサンライズ どんな輝きの中も
Shine, sunrise! Even in any glitter,
強いきらめき
with a powerful sparkle!
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if only a millimeter gets through!
チャージ チャレンジ 全力アクセル
Charge, challenge, and full-throttle acceleration!
がんばる君へ
To you, who are doing your best!
一番乗りのスマイルを送る スバルチャンネル
Sending the very first smile on Subaru Channel!
Everyday 悩んでないで
Every day, don't worry about a thing,
みんなで
everyone together!
ブルーな気持ちに ズバッと駆けつけ
Rushing in to chase away your blue feelings...
お助けしちゃうヒーロー
...as a hero who will come to your rescue!
弱いハートじゃ いられないから
Because we can't stay with weak hearts,
つよつよで行きましょう
let's go strong and mighty!
はらはら水着で
In a heart-fluttering swimsuit,
ドキドキのときめきたい
I want to have a heart-pounding, exciting time!
いつでもおいでよ
Come on over anytime!
1年中パラダイスとことん
Enjoying paradise to the absolute fullest all year round!
メモリートラブル吹き飛ばそう
Let's blow away any memory troubles!
上がれサンライズ どんな暗闇の中も
Rise, sunrise! Even in any darkness,
まぶしく照らす
shining so brightly!
君に見つけてもらえた
You managed to find me...
それだけでもう運命なんだ
and just that makes it destiny!
もっとずっと 道は続いていく
The road keeps going on and on...
夢に向かって
towards our dreams!
一緒に来てくれるかな
I wonder if you'll come with me?
その手をとって走れ
Take my hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで
I'll take you there, everyone together!
ささやく 恥ずかしいけれど
I whisper, though it's a bit embarrassing...
伝えたい想い 今なら言える
but these feelings I want to convey, I can say them now!
君のエールが 力になるよ
Your cheers give me strength!
いつも元気を 分けてくれて
You always share your energy with me,
がんばっていけるんだ
so I can keep doing my best!
笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
I can truly spend my days smiling!
ありがとうの気持ちを 歌え！
Singing my feelings of gratitude!
サンライズ どんな輝きの中も
Sunrise! Even in any glitter,
強いきらめき
with a powerful sparkle!
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if only a millimeter gets through!
もっとずっと 道は続いていく
The road keeps going on and on...
夢に向かって
towards our dreams!
一緒に来てくれるかな
I wonder if you'll come with me?
その手をとって走れ
Take my hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで
I'll take you there, everyone together!
君と駆ける スバル
Subaru, running along with you!
大空スバル7周年ライブ！始まる！始まるー！
Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live is starting! It's starting!
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always cause you so much trouble,
いつもさんざん困らせちゃうけど
and I always end up making things hard for you,
それでも隣にいてくれる
but even so, you stay right by my side.
君のそばにずっと
I'll stay by your side forever.
曖昧な言葉じゃ
With vague words,
真面目な君には伝わらない
I can't get through to your serious heart.
頑丈なそのハートを
That sturdy heart of yours...
覗いてみたい
I want to take a look inside,
溶かしてみたい
I want to melt it down!
そんな時こんな魔法はどうかな？
At times like this, how about a little magic like this?
何が出るかな？
What will happen, I wonder?
やっちゃえ！
Go for it!
せーの！
Ready, set!
try try try
あやふやだって
Even if it's uncertain,
いいの！いいの！
it's fine! It's fine!
Which one to pick?
Watch me do magic!
あらら想像以上の展開
Oh wow, things turned out beyond imagination!
もう止められないのよ
Now i just can't stop,
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
溢れる想いで空回り
My overflowing feelings just go in circles.
振りかけるhappyなイメージ
Sprinkling on some happy images...
で振り回すfancyなマジック
and swinging some fancy magic around!
また君に
Once again,
くどくど言われちゃうけど ほら
you'll end up scolding me, but look...
こんなday by dayがいい
days like these, day by day, are just right!
なんていっぱいでっかい
How huge and full of things!
あの日から Falling in love with you
Falling in love with you since that day
変わらないから ずっと Only you
It won't change, you'll always be my only one
だから ほら
So, look,
うだうだ してる場合じゃないの
this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
掴めハッピーエンディング
Let's grab a happy ending!
いつまでも 隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep laughing by your side forever!
いつも仲間はずれで
Always being left out,
ひとりぼっちの毎日
living lonely days...
そんな私の前に
Before someone like me,
あらわれた君は
you appeared,
同じ寂しさを抱えている
carrying the same loneliness.
とてもとても優しい人
You are a very, very kind person.
今も心配事は多いけど
Though there are still many worries,
もう私も君も一人じゃない
neither you nor I are alone anymore.
騒がしくて愛しいこの日々が
These noisy and beloved days,
ずっと続きますように
I hope they continue forever.
3, 2, 1
飛ばせハッピーなイメージ
Send flying a happy image!
とびきりのFancyなマジック
An extraordinary, fancy magic!
また君に くどくど言われそうだけれど
I feel like you'll lecture me again, but...
そんなDay by dayがいい
I love that kind of day-by-day.
あの日から Falling in love with you
Falling in love with you since that day
気付いて欲しいの Loving you
I want you to notice my love for you
だから ほら
So, look,
うだうだ してる場合じゃないの
this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
次はどんなプランニング
What kind of planning is next?
そしてまた今日もハプニング
And once again, there's a happening today!
明日はどんな
Tomorrow, what kind of
おかしなことが起こるかな
strange things will happen?
ずっと 隣で見ててね
Always watch over me by my side.
ハッピーなイメージ
A happy image...
Fancyなマジック
...fancy magic...
ハッピーなイメージ
...happy image...
Fancyなマジック
...fancy magic!
ハイタッチ☆メモリー (LIVE High-Touch☆Summer ver.)
[Song: High-Touch☆Memory (LIVE High-Touch☆Summer ver.)]
いっせーの で 君と だけ ！
On three... just with you!
もしかして居眠り体験？と
Could it be a napping experience? And
もったいないよ 今日はサンデー
what a waste, today is Sunday!
楽しいこと やりたいこと
Fun things, things I want to do,
Wake up ! 始めようよ
Wake up! Let's get started!
めくりめく季節 君と
The revolving seasons, with you,
次のステージへ
to the next stage.
声を合わせ 扉開けて
Raise our voices, open the door,
駆け出せ 迷わずに
and run without hesitating!
転んでも かっこ悪くても イイじゃない
Even if you fall or look uncool, that's okay!
Stand up ! イメージもっと重ねて行く その先で
Stand up! Keep layering the image, beyond that!
いっせーの で 君と だけ ！
On three... just with you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて
High-touch, clap your hands,
奏でる メロディーを
and play the melody!
合図に 走り出せ Go!",
On cue, start running, Go!
君となら こわくない
If I'm with you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手 たたいて
High-touch, clap hand-to-hand,
重ねる そのメモリーは
and those memories we build up,
明日への エネルギー
will be the energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Come on, let's go further ahead.
君となら Happy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a Happy Lucky Life!
あの日みた夢の続き
The continuation of the dream we saw that day,
追い付く その日まで
until the day we catch up to it.
涙なんて 振り切るくらい
To the point of shaking off tears,
もっと スピードアップ
speed up even more!
どんな未来に なっても 後悔しないよ
No matter what future comes, I won't regret it.
自分自身 選んだ道
The path I chose myself,
踏み出せ 迷わずに
step forward without hesitating!
落ち込んで 進めなくなった時は
When you're feeling down and can't move forward,
Wake up ! 思い返す 夢見た頃の記憶を
Wake up! Recall the memories of when we dreamed.
手と手で 奏でる かなえる しらべも 夢も
Our melodies played hand-in-hand, and our dreams,
君とだけ！
only with you!
ハイタッチ その度に
High-touch! Every time we do,
繋がっていく心
our hearts connect.
一人じゃないことを そう
Yes, that we're not alone,
気付かせてくれたよね
you made me realize.
ハイタッチ 手と手 たたいて
High-touch! Clap hand-to-hand,
奏でる そのメロディーが
and the melody we play,
世界に届くまで
until it reaches the world,
この夢は続いていく
this dream will keep continuing!
君とも Happy Lucky Live!
With you, it's a Happy Lucky Live!
くじけて 歩けない日は
On days when you're discouraged and can't walk,
おんぶしてあげる 君を
I will carry you on my back.
ほら見て そっちの方が
Look, from that direction,
強い地面 踏み込める
you can step onto firmer ground.
めぐりめぐる日々を
The revolving days...
辿り夢見たステージへ
...tracing them to the stage I dreamed of.
届くその日を見つめて
Gazing at the day it reaches...
起こそう君とだけ！
...let's wake it up just with you!
おこそうは君とだけ
Let's make it happen, only with you!
手と手を鳴らす度
Every time we clap our hands,
小さなビッグバン
a tiny Big Bang occurs.
無限のその力を
Receiving that infinite power,
受けて進め！
move forward!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて
High-five, clapping hands together,
奏でるメロディーを
playing the melody.
合図に走り出せ Go!
Start running at the signal, go!
君となら こわくない
If it's with you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて
High-five, clapping hands hand in hand,
重ねる そのメモリーは
those piled-up memories
明日へのエネルギー
are the energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Come on, let's go further ahead.
君となら Happy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a happy lucky life!
というわけでみなさん！
And with that, everyone!
大空スバル7周年記念ライブ『LOVE ME!』にお越しくださり
Thank you so much for coming to Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live, "LOVE ME!"
ありがとうございます！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
ちわーす！このライブにきてる
Hello! For those here at this live...
大空スバルです！よろしくお願いします！ということで
...I'm Oozora Subaru! Please look forward to it! So...
ついに『LOVE ME!』が始まる、始まるー！
Finally, "LOVE ME!" is starting! It's starting!
今日のですね、配信のハッシュタグは
The hashtag for today's stream...
右上のこちらになりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
...is right up here in the top right, so please use it!
いっぱいに『大空スバル7周年ライブ』をつけて
Please add the hashtag #大空スバル7周年LIVE...
たくさん呟いてください。スバルもチェックしたいと思います。
...and tweet a lot! I'll be checking them too!
そしてみなさん、気づきましたか？
And everyone, did you notice?
なんと、今までも可愛かったんですけど、でも！
I mean, I was cute before, but...
より可愛くしていただきました！
...they made me even cuter!
ニュースバルです！よろしくお願いします。
This is the new Subaru! Please treat me well!
どうですか？可愛い？
How is it? Is it cute?
可愛いーー！あはは！
So cute! Haha!
ぜひですね、たくさんスクショとね
Please take lots of screenshots...
ポストか、ポストしてください！
...and post, please post them!
そしてですね、スバルはですね
And also, for Subaru...
通常のですねスバルもね、見てほしいので
...I want you to see my usual self too,
ちょっと着替えてきていいですか？着替えてきます。じゃあ行ってきます。
so is it okay if I change? I'll go change! Off I go!
わー！
Wow!
うわーー！
Whoa!
わっ！通常衣装のニュースバル！
Whoa! It's the new Subaru in my usual outfit!
そしてなんと、帽子がない！
And amazingly, I don't have my hat!
ついに取れるようになった！やったーー！
I can finally take it off! Yay!
ついに取れるようになりました！
I can finally take it off now!
どうですか？可愛いですか？
How is it? Do I look cute?
可愛いですか？
Do I look cute?
とってもね、えー、より可愛く作っていただきました。
They made it look so, so much cuter.
髪の毛もね、サラサラ！
My hair is so silky too!
もう本当にね、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so, so much!
そして！可愛いといえば、なんとこちらのステージ！
And speaking of cute, look at this stage!
とてもね、可愛いです。
It's so cute!
スバルあのすごくゲームが好きなので
Subaru loves games so much,
このピクセルっぽい感じでね、今年はね、作っていただきました！イェーイ！
so they made it in this pixel art style this year! Yay!
スバルドダックもいる！
Subaru Duck is here too!
そして、なんといってもこの
And above all, these...
ピクセルスバとも！
...pixel Subatomos!
もうめっちゃ可愛いです。
They are so incredibly cute!
これが一番見せたかったと言っても過言ではない！
It's no exaggeration to say this is what I wanted to show you most!
ということで、こんな素敵なステージでさせていただいて
So, being able to perform on such a wonderful stage...
あーー！なんと！しれっと着替えてきました！
Ah! Somehow, I quietly changed back!
こんにちは！やっぱりね、アイドル衣装をね、着てね、
Hello! Yes, I want to perform in my idol outfit.
やっていきたいと思います。ぜひ、アイドル衣装スバルもですね、
Please take lots of screenshots of me in my idol outfit too...
いっぱいスクショとって
...and post them!
ポストしてください。
Please post them!
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you so much!
はい、ということでここまではなんと、
Alright, so up until now,
『ぷりあーれ』、『Watch Me』、『ハイタッチ☆メモリー』のね、
I performed "Pliare", "Watch Me", and "High-Touch☆Memory"...
3曲をお届けしたんですけど、
...these three songs!
ま、すべてですね、スバルにとって思い出深い楽曲で、
They are all very memorable songs for Subaru.
特に『ぷりあーれ』は絶対に
Especially "Pliare"—
このニュースバルになったら、もう1番にね、みんなにね、披露したいなと思っていたので、
I really wanted to perform it first once I got this new look,
夢叶いしもなってます！
so it's a dream come true!
メッチャ嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
はい、ということで、もうね、ここからはですね、なんと、
Alright, so from here on out...
何が起こるかわからない！ゲストがでてくるかもしれないし、
...who knows what will happen! Guests might appear,
でてこないかもしれない、もう何が起こるかわからない！ということで、
or maybe not! Who knows! So...
えー、そんなライブお楽しみに！
...please look forward to the live!
このあとも、もうどんどんね、盛り上がって楽しんでいくぞーー！
Let's keep pumping things up and having fun after this too!
始まる始まるーー！
Here we go! Let's get started!
わたしの全力受けとめて♡
"Accept my full power ♡"
きゅっきゅん らった ちゅら めに めに
Kyu-kyun ratta chu-ra meni-meni
きゅっきゅん らった ちゅら しゅき しゅき しゅー しゅき
Kyu-kyun ratta chu-ra shu-ki shu-ki shu-shu-ki
きゅっきゅん らたっちゅら
Kyu-kyun, ratatchura,
めにめに oh yeah
many-many, oh yeah!
キョンキョンキョン、とくんとー？
Throb, throb, throb, thump-thump?
てんきゅっきゅん
Thank-kyu-kyun!
たとえば、タイムループなんかしたっちゃって
Even if, say, we ended up in a time loop,
運命で選んじゃうのは キミ
The one I'd choose by fate is you!
イェーイ イェーイ
Yay, yay!
わたしと いったいぜんたい いやぜったい！
Between you and me, absolutely, no, definitely!
シンデレラフィットなのは そう、キミ
A Cinderella fit, yes, that's you!
おっおー おっおー
Oh-oh, oh-oh!
わたしが 何度も負けて落ち込んだって
Even if I lose again and again and get depressed,
めげずに特訓付き合っちゃって
You don't give up and train with me anyway,
モチベあげるだけぶち上げちゃって
Raising my motivation, pumping me up!
もうなんなん？なんなんなんなん！？
Seriously, what? What, what, what, what!?
ステップアップめっちぇっちゃって
Step-stepping up so much!
勝手に一緒に喜び合って
And we celebrate together without even asking!
う…感激してもしても足りないんじゃ〜っ！
Ugh... no matter how grateful I am, it's never enough!
形だけなんてナンセンス
Just keeping up appearances is nonsense.
形ないものがいいんです
Things without physical shape are what's best.
えっとね…それはなんといいますか……
Um, well... how do I put this...
あっ、待って待って
Ah, wait, wait!
今ここで伝えたいんです！
I want to tell you right here and now!
つきなみだけど届けたい想い
It might be cliché, but this is the feeling I want to send you:
「こんなに大きくなりました」
“Look how big I've grown!”
だから
So,
超many-manyめな約束ドドっとプリーズ保存
Give me tons of super many-many promises, please!
もりもりmanyめにお返しするから！
Because I'll pay you back with heaps and heaps of love!
いつだって
Anytime,
しゅーきしゅーきしゅーきしゅき シュプリームなオネガイきいて！
Listen to my love-love-love-love, supreme request!
わたしあいた〜い
I want to see you!
day by day
超many-manyギュギュギュッとエールをぷり〜ず
Tightly wrap super many-many cheers for me, please!
絶対絶対バイで返すから！
Because I'll definitely, definitely return it double!
手渡しじゃ何年かかるかな
If I handed them out in person, how many years would it take?
ヘビーすぎない！？でもねいいんじゃない？？
Isn't that too heavy!? But hey, isn't it fine??
Gimme！！いつも愛をア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ
Gimme!! Thank you so much for always giving me your love!
甘いだけじゃダメだけどね
Being sweet alone isn't enough, but...
今日くらいは許してよ…hum
Please forgive me just for today... hum~
大事な話だからもうちぇ〜〜〜っと
Since this is important, just a little bit more...
気合だけで言えるかな
Can I say it with just willpower?
精神誠意をきいてくれますか？
Will you listen to my utmost sincerity?
あ〜〜
Ah~~
だ・か・ら
S-o,
超many-manyめな約束ドドっとプリーズ
Give me tons of super many-many promises, please!
もりもりmanyめにお返しするから！
Because I'll pay you back with heaps and heaps of love!
いつだって
Anytime,
しゅーきしゅーきしゅーきしゅき シュプリームなオネガイきいて！
Listen to my love-love-love-love, supreme request!
わたしあいた〜い
I want to see you!
day by day
超many-manyギュギュギュッとエールをぷり〜ず
Tightly wrap super many-many cheers for me, please!
絶対絶対バイで返すから！
Because I'll definitely, definitely return it double!
手渡しで何年かかっても
Even if it takes many years to do in person,
伝えたいじゃない！届けたいじゃない！
I want to tell you! I want to send it to you!
Gimme！！いつも愛をア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ
Gimme!! Thank you so much for always giving me your love!
きゅっきゅん らたっちゅら めにめに oh yeah
Kyu-kyun, ratatchura, many-many, oh yeah!
きゅん きゅんきゅん とくんとー？
Throb, throb, throb, thump-thump?
きゅん きゅん きゅん きゅん きゅん きゅん！
Throb, throb, throb, throb, throb, throb!
ず〜〜っとよろしくね
“Let's stay together forever!”
ゆらゆらり はらはらり いろとりどり みだれざき
Swaying gently, fluttering down, multi-colored, blooming in wild profusion.
花の町思いだす この空から
I remember the town of flowers from this sky.
百花繚乱
[Title: Hyakka Ryoran]
ひょんな出来事から やってきたこの場所は
This place I've stumbled upon by a strange twist of fate,
はるか遠くにあった きらびやかな舞台
Was a dazzling stage that used to be so far away.
はっとするほど 鮮やかな世界があるんだと知った
I learned that there exists a world so vivid it takes my breath away.
あなたの無理難題に 答えていくその度に
Every time I step up to meet your unreasonable demands,
あっと思わせるような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
With our unexpected, out-of-this-world solutions,
たどり着いたその先に 新しい景色が待っているんだ
A brand new landscape awaits us at our final destination.
摩訶不思議なミステリー 次から次に起こるたび
Every time a mysterious, incomprehensible mystery occurs one after another,
巧妙なからくりも 暴いてみせましょう
I will expose even the most clever tricks for you.
どんな難題でも タネや仕掛けはあるんだ
No matter how difficult the problem, there's always a trick or mechanism.
複雑要素は気にしない 必ずや導き出すから
I don't care about the complex elements, because I will surely find the answer.
あぁこの場所で触れた 人の悲しみや喜びがある
Ah, there are sorrows and joys of people I've touched in this place.
その一つ一つが 心を震わせる
Every single one of them makes my heart tremble.
はっとしちゃうほど 鮮やかな世界がここにあるんだ
A world so vivid it makes my heart skip a beat is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 答えていく毎日に
In these daily lives of responding to your unreasonable demands,
あっと思わせるような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
With our unexpected, out-of-this-world solutions...
辿り着いたその先に
Beyond the place I've finally reached,
新しい私が待っているんだ
a brand new me is waiting.
あの頃は
Back then,
想像もしていない
I could never have imagined
未来が咲き始めている
this future that has begun to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
Maybe days like these aren't so bad after all.
ゆらゆらに ひらひらに
Swaying and fluttering...
離れては寄り添って
drifting apart, then drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ
Entrusting myself to the gentle breeze,
優雅に舞う
I dance so gracefully.
あの夢も アコガレも
That dream, and those aspirations too...
落書きのままぼやけて
remain blurred like scribbles,
消える寸前
right on the verge of fading away.
「コレがいいの？」
"Is this what you want?"
「これでいいの？」
"Is this really okay?"
ふてくされてる鏡に
I've asked myself in the sulking mirror
何度も問いかけた
over and over again.
泣きたい日も
On days I want to cry,
くじけそうな日も
and on days I feel like giving up,
乗り越えよう
let's rise above them!
光 希望を 浴びなきゃ
Unless we bathe in light and hope,
夢というツボミは
the bud we call a dream
開かないから
will never bloom.
Are you ready GO!
走り出そう！
Let's start running!
取り急ぎ さぁ スタート！
First things first, let's start!
うつむかない！
No looking down!
ふりむかない！
No looking back!
明日は絶対もっと Shiny!
Tomorrow will definitely be even more shiny!
ジブン次第！
It's all up to me!
掴め未来！
Seize the future!
今すぐスタートボタン
Let's press the start button
押してみよう
right now!
私は
I know that I...
こんなんじゃないはず！
...am not supposed to be like this!
あきらめも 言い訳も
Giving up and making excuses...
とりまとめリスタート！
pack them all up and restart!
「たられば」に すがるには
To cling to "what ifs"...
まだまだ若すぎじゃない？
aren't we still way too young for that?
七転び 八起きで GO!
Fall seven times, stand up eight, GO!
何度もリセットボタン
Press the reset button as many times as it takes!
どんな夢も
No matter what the dream is,
きっと
it surely...
困難じゃないはず
...won't be impossible!
信じてみよう
Let's believe in ourselves.
私は
I know that I...
こんなんじゃないはず！
...am not supposed to be like this!
こんなんじゃない！
This isn't how it ends!
Breakdown, breakdown!
Listen, girl!
Listen, boy!
Breakdown, breakdown!
3, 2, 1, Let's go!
Shining justice 芽生えて
Shining justice, budding within me.
Brand new bed town 交差する息吹
Brand new bedtown, where our breaths intersect.
岬から潮風
A sea breeze from the cape...
トンネル抜けて鉄塔へ
...passes through the tunnel to the steel tower.
引かれ合い小道に迷い込む
Drawn together, we wander into a side street.
ココロに
In my heart...
溶け込む影
...shadows melt away,
照らす黄金の "Spirits"
illuminating the golden "Spirits."
それは守り抜く光
That is the light we will protect to the end.
Let the voice of love take you higher
集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
with our gathered power, even transcending time.
1999 Bizarre Summer
巡る勇気で生きる町 Great Days
...living in this town with circulating courage, Great Days.
抜け出せる街
In this escapable town...
Great Days
Breakdown breakdown
SHINING JUSTICE 芽生え始めてくる
Shining justice starts to bud...
Brand-new bed town すれ違う景色
In this brand-new bedtown, passing scenery...
雲の切れ間に射す光がほら降り注ぎ
Look, light shines down through cracks in the clouds...
いにしえの地より導き出された
Guided forth from an ancient land...
魂が吸い込む
...souls are drawn in.
きらめき
A sparkle...
導く街
...guiding us through the town.
たぎる黄金のスピリット
A surging golden spirit...
それは果てしない
...it is endless.
絆
Our bonds.
Let the voice of love give you answer!
別れの時さえ 砕けぬ意志で
Even at the time of parting, with an unbreakable will.
1999 Bizarre Summer
自分乗り越え 掴み取れ未来
Overcome yourself and seize the future!
Great Days
Breakdown breakdown
Let the voice of love take you higher!
集まる力で時さえ超えて
With gathered strength, even crossing through time.
Let the voice of love give you answer!
別れの時さえ 砕けぬ意志で
Even at the time of parting, with an unbreakable will.
1999 Bizarre Summer
交わす勇気が 生む讃歌
The courage we share creates a hymn...
Great Days!
Breakdown breakdown
というわけで！『Great Days』をお届けしましたー！
So, that was our performance of 'Great Days'!
みんな楽しんでくれましたかー？
Did everyone enjoy it?
えー、ここまではですね、まず『ウマ娘』から『ユメヲカケル！』。
So, up until now, first was 'Yume wo Kakeru!' from 'Uma Musume'.
この曲はですね、スバルもうめっちゃね、この曲元々大好きで絶対にやろうって決めてたんですけど...
I absolutely love this song and had decided I definitely wanted to perform it......
あのー、その結果ね、見事ね、もうウマ娘のね、アプリめっちゃやるようになりました。ありがとうございます！
And as a result, I've ended up playing a ton of the Uma Musume app. Thank you so much!
そんなね、大好きな楽曲をですね、みんなとできてとっても楽しかったです！ありがとうございます。
I had so much fun performing such a beloved song with everyone! Thank you very much.
そして、続いて！『百花繚乱』でね、かっこよく踊りました。どうでしたか？
And next, we did a cool dance to 'Hyakka Ryouran'. How was it?
この、ひらひらりがですね、結構難しくて、頑張ったんですけど、見てくれましたか？
Waving this fan around was actually quite difficult, but I did my best. Did you catch it?
でもすごーくね、踊って楽しかったです！
But it was so much fun to dance to!
そしてですね、ファンサ！もうこの曲はですね、夢叶えしものとなった時点で絶対にやろうって思ってたんですけど、
And then, 'Fansa'! I decided that once my dream came true, I absolutely had to perform this song,
えー、ノエルちゃんとね、スバルにね、もう絶対にペンライトを振ってほしいと思って、もう呼ばせていただきました！
and I really wanted Noel-chan and everyone to wave penlights for me, so I invited them!
どうだったかな、みんな？楽しんでもらえたらとっても嬉しいです。
How was it, everyone? I'd be so happy if you enjoyed it.
引いて、『Great Days』はですね、もうスバルの大好きなね、ジョジョ4部の曲なんですけど、
And 'Great Days' is from JoJo Part 4, which I absolutely love,
この、もう絶対、もうこれでバトンをするんだと、こうやってぐるぐるぐるぐる回してね、今年もね、飛ばさせていただいたんですけど、
and I was determined to twirl the baton like this. I even got to send it flying again this year!
みんな、スバルの『魂』と書いて『プライド』と読む、この魂のバトンを、見ていただけましたか？
Did everyone see my baton of 'soul'—written as 'soul' but read as 'pride'?
もう、もうすごかったんだから、本当に！
Seriously, it was absolutely amazing!
ということで、そんなスバルのですね、こだわりと思いがいっぱい詰まったパートにさせていただきました！
So, that was a segment filled with all of my focus and passion!
そしてなんと！ここからは、嬉しいお知らせとなっております！
And now, we have some exciting news!
なんと、大空スバル7周年記念ライブの、グッズ販売告知！
We are announcing the merchandise sale for Oozora Subaru's 7th anniversary live!
こちらをご覧ください！
Please take a look at this!
グッズは4種類あります！めちゃめちゃある！ということで、早速見ていきましょう！
There are four types of merchandise! That's a lot! Let's check them out right away!
イラストはしぐれうい先生に描いていただきました！かあちゃんいつもありがとう！
The illustrations were drawn by Shigure Ui-sensei! Thank you as always, Mom!
イラストテーマは『王道アイドルスバル』です！
The theme of the illustration is 'Royal Road Idol Subaru'!
それでは詳細を見ていきましょう。まずは、こちら！
Now, let's look at the details. First up is this!
『スバルがファンサ！ラバーマット』！
'Subaru's Fansa! Rubber Mat'!
こちらの商品はですね、王道アイドルのスバルが描かれた...
This item features our royal road idol, Subaru...
書いてあるラバーマットになります！
This is the rubber mat!
以前ラバーマットを出したのは、えっと、4年前なので
The last time I released a rubber mat was, let's see, 4 years ago,
当時買えなかった人もね、
so those who couldn't buy it back then,
前のご使ってて、もうボロボロになっちゃったよっていう人も
or those whose old ones are now completely worn out,
ぜひ新しくチェックしてみてください！
please be sure to check out the new one!
そして、続いてはこちら！
And up next is this!
スバルがファンサ！カードスリーブ！
Subaru Blows a Kiss! Card Sleeves!
こちらはですね、ラバーマットに合わせて、カードスリーブも出してみました！
For this, I tried making card sleeves to match the rubber mat!
ラバーマットと合わせて使えば、スバルに応援されているような気持ちになれるかも、ということで
If you use them together with the rubber mat, you might feel like Subaru is cheering you on,
ぜひこちらも要チェックですよ！
so please be sure to check this out as well!
そして、続いてこちら！
And next is this!
マスコット大集合カードケース！イェーイ！
Mascot Assembly Card Case! Yay!
カードスリーブときたらやっぱり、ケースも必要でしょ、ということで
Since we have card sleeves, we obviously need a case too,
もうスバルの、スバルドダックから、
so we have Subaru's Subarudo Duck,
なんと！わたウサギまで！そしてスバともも、というようなね、
and incredibly, even Watausagi! And Subatomo too!
たくさんみんなが集まった、えーカードケースを作ってみました。
I made a card case where so many of everyone gathered together.
側面はですね、カードを見せつけられる窓がついているので
On the side, there is a window where you can display your card,
今回のカードスリーブをバシュッとさして見せるもよし、
so you can pop this card sleeve in to show it off,
そのね、切り札を見せつけるもよし、ということで
or show off your trump card!
ぜひこちらもチェックしてみてください。
So please check this out as well.
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, here is this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー 動物パジャマ衣装ver.！
Plushie Keychain: Animal Pajamas Costume ver.!
こちらはですね、なんかスバル自身のぬいぐるみって、あまり出してないから、あーもう、みたいなことを思ったので
For this, I realized I haven't released many plushies of Subaru herself,
ちょっとね、アイドル衣装と対になるイメージの、オフっぽい動物パジャマ衣装で作ってみました！
so I made one in an off-duty animal pajamas costume, meant to pair with the idol costume!
ぜひね、このかわちいスバルもね、色んなところに連れ回して、みてください！
Please take this cute Subaru around with you to all sorts of places!
そしてなんと、フルセット購入特典もあります！それでは、こちら、ドン！
And on top of that, there is a full set purchase bonus! Here it is, bam!
ステッカーがなんとね、今回ついております。とっても可愛いです！
A sticker is included this time! It's so cute!
スバルずっと前から、ステッカー出してみたいなってずっと思ってたので、今回ですね、夢が叶って嬉しいです！
I've wanted to release a sticker for a long time, so I'm so happy my dream came true!
ぜひみんなのね、お気に入りの場所にペタッと貼ってみてください！
Please stick it on your favorite spot!
そしてでは、改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！ドン！
Now, here is the full set once again! Bam!
やっぱりね、買うならね、シールもついてお得なフルセットの方がいいかも！
After all, if you're buying, the full set with the sticker is a much better deal!
ということで、ぜひね、チェックしてみてください！
So please be sure to check it out!
以上！大空スバル7周年記念ライブのグッズ情報でした！
That's all for Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live merch info!
どれもですね、素敵なグッズに仕上がっておりますので、ぜひですね、要チェックだ！
Everything turned out to be wonderful merch, so definitely check them out!
絶対に、絶対にチェックしてくださいね。よろしくお願いします！
Please, please check them out. Thank you so much!
はい！そしてですね、なんと、この衣装での、ニュースバル、ちょっとね
Yes! And also, my new look in this costume is...
可愛いのでとっても、ぜひスクリーンショット撮っていただきたいです！わー！
really cute, so I'd love for you to take screenshots! Yay!
あ、そっか、後ろ向いたら撮れないや。
Oh right, if I turn around you can't take them.
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
スバルのこのね、衣装のね、好きポイントはですね、この後ろの
My favorite point of this costume is the back,
とっても可愛い、
the very cute...
とっても可愛いリボンがですね！
very cute ribbon!
可愛い！
Cute!
どうですか？
How is it?
うわー！可愛い！え、マジで語彙力ないな、今日。
Wow! Cute! Man, I really have no vocabulary today.
でも、本当に可愛いんで、ぜひみんな、いっぱいね、ポストしてください。よろしくお願いします。
But it's really cute, so please post lots of pictures. Thank you!
そしてですね、こんなに楽しいライブも、
And now, this incredibly fun live show is...
もう、なんと終盤！うわー！
already near the end! No way!
そしてここからはですね、もうラストに向けてですね、
And from here on out, heading towards the end,
バーッと駆け抜けていきたいと思いますので、ぜひみんなもね、最後まで楽しんでいただけるとすごく嬉しいです！
I'm going to run right through it, so I'd be so happy if you all enjoy it until the very end!
はい！ということで、
Yes! So,
それじゃあ、もうラストだよ！
well then, it's the final part!
始めちゃっていいわけ？始めちゃうよ。
Is it okay to start? I'm gonna start it.
ということで、それではですね、
And with that, well then...
よし！始めたいと思います。よいしょ、よいしょ。ポーズとって。
Alright! I'm going to start. Let's strike a pose.
はい！
Yes!
それでは聴いてください。ray
Please listen to... "ray."
ray / 作詞・作曲：藤原基央
[Title: ray / Lyrics & Composition: Motoo Fujiwara]
お別れしたのはもっと前の事だったような
It seems like it was a long time ago that we said goodbye
悲しい光は閉じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
I've been wearing out my heels, keeping the sad light inside
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
When I was with you I could see it, now I can't
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
Looking blankly at a transparent comet, but that's all I'm looking for
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I often sang a song, a melody just for that moment
寂しくなんかなかったよ ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
I wasn't lonely, because I could properly feel lonely
寂しくなれたから
Because I was able to feel lonely
いつまでどこまでなんて
"How long and how far," I ask
正常か異常かなんて
"Normal or abnormal," I ask
考える暇も無い程
With no time to even think,
歩くのは大変だ
walking is so hard
楽しい方がずっといいよ
It's much better to have fun
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll just fake it and smile
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
Don't worry, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
won't go away even if you forget
理想で作った道を
The road we made with our ideals...
現実が塗り替えていくよ
reality will rewrite
思い出はその軌跡の上で
Memories, on those tracks...
輝きになって残っている
will remain as a shine
お別れしたのは何で
I wonder why we said goodbye,
何のためだったんだろうな
and for what?
悲しい光が僕の影を
The sad light stretches...
前に長く伸ばしている
my shadow long before me
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever
時間がある時眠るよ
When I have time, I sleep
夢だと解るその中で
In the midst of what I know to be a dream,
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll see you and then go again
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from a clear sky,
終わらない暗闇にも
in the never-ending darkness
星を思い浮かべたなら
if I think of stars,
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'll soon be in the galaxy
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
靴を新しくしても
even if I get new shoes...
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
Don't worry, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
won't go away even if you forget
伝えたかった事が
There's something I wanted to tell you
きっとあったんだろうな
I'm sure of it
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど
It's probably a cliché, but...
こんなにも
so much so...
お別れした事は
What we said goodbye to...
出会った事と繋がっている
is connected to what we met
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet...
透明だから無くならない
will never disappear because it's transparent
〇×△どれかだなんて
Circle, cross, triangle... which one is it?
皆と比べてどうかだなんて
"How do I compare to everyone else," I ask
確かめる間も無い程
With no time to even check,
生きるのは最高だ
living is the best!
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll just fake it and smile
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
Don't worry, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
won't go away even if you forget
大丈夫だ この光の
Don't worry, at the beginning...
始まりには
of this light...
君がいる
you're here
シルエット
Silhouette
いっせーのーせで
In one go,
踏み込むゴーライン 僕らは
stepping over the goal line, we...
何も 何も
still don't, still don't...
まだ知らぬ
know anything at all
一線越えて
Crossing the line,
振り返るともうない 僕らは
looking back, it's already gone, we...
何も 何も
still don't, still don't...
まだ知らぬ
know anything at all
うだっておだっておだってく
Fired up, fired up, getting fired up
煌めく汗がこぼれるのさ
Bursting with glistening sweat
覚えてないことも
Even the things we don't remember...
たくさんあっただろう
there are probably a lot of them
誰も
Everyone...
彼も
...and anyone...
シルエット
...is but a silhouette.
大事にしてたもの
Pretending to have forgotten...
忘れたふりをしたんだよ
...the things we used to cherish.
なにもないよ
It's nothing,
笑えるさ
we can just laugh it off.
いっせーのーで
On the count of three,
思い出す少年
remembering that boy we used to be,
僕らは
we...
何もかも
...wanted to have...
欲しがった
...absolutely everything.
わかってるって
I know,
あぁ気づいてるって
ah, I've noticed...
時計の
...that the hands...
針は
...of the clock,
日々は
these days,
止まらない
will never stop.
奪って 奪って 奪ってく
They keep stealing, stealing, stealing away...
流れる
...flowing by...
時と流れる記憶
...time and drifting memories...
遠く 遠く 遠くになって
...getting further, further, and further away.
覚えてないことも
Even though there are many things...
たくさんあっただろう保存
...we don't remember,
誰も
everyone...
彼も
...and anyone...
シルエット
...is but a silhouette.
恐れてやまぬこと
Pretending to not know...
知らないふりをしたんだよ保存
...the things we are so afraid of.
なにもないよ
It's nothing,
笑えるさ
we can just laugh it off.
ひらりと ひらりと 舞ってる
Fluttering and fluttering, dancing in the air,
木の葉のよに揺れ
swaying like leaves on a tree.
こと無く
Without a worry...
焦燥なく
...or any impatience,
過ごしていたいよ保存
I want to spend my days.
覚えてないことも
There were many things...
たくさんあったけど保存保存
...that we didn't remember,
きっと ずっと
but surely, there is something...
変わらないものがあること保存
...that will never change.
を教えてくれた保存
You taught me that,
あなたは消えぬ消えぬ
and you, my unforgettable...
シルエット
...silhouette.
大事にしたいもの保存
Clutching what I want to cherish,
持って大人になるんだ
I will grow up into an adult.
どんな 時も
No matter the time,
離さずに
without ever letting go,
守り続けよう
I'll keep on protecting them.
そしたら いつの日にか
Then, one of these days,
なにもかもを
...we can laugh...
笑えるさ
...at everything.
ひらりと ひらりと 舞ってる
Fluttering and fluttering, dancing in the air,
木の葉が飛んでゆく
the leaves fly away.
Wow Wow
Wow...
描いた未知の
The canvas of the unknown that I drew,
キャンバス重ねる景色
layering over the scenery.
繋いでみて
Try to connect them,
繰り返していく衝動保存
this impulse that keeps repeating.
揺らいだ
The world expanding...
目の前に広がる世界
...before my wavering eyes,
星屑のメロディ
carrying the stardust melody...
歌に乗せた
...upon my song.保存
クラッと鮮やかに
Dizzy and vivid,
眩ませるように
as if to dazzle,
駆け抜けるよ スターライト
I'll run through, starlight!
We can fly
そう 僕らは
Yes, we...
いつしか 夢の中
...were drawn into the dream...
惹かれて
...before we knew it.
ただ がむしゃらに走り続けたよ保存
I just kept running recklessly.
無限の宇宙に保存
Ringing through the infinite universe,保存
響いた 君を照らす声は保存
the voice that shines on you...
どこへだって きらり 飛んでゆけるんだ保存
...can sparkle and fly anywhere!
愉快な仲間と
With my cheerful friends,
歩いた非日常
the extraordinary days we walked.
掴んでみて
Try to grasp...
指先の一等星
...the first-magnitude star at your fingertips.
滲んでゆく
Blurring away,
目の前に広がった限界は
the limits that spread before us.
みんなの手 重ねて
With everyone's hands overlapping,
ぶっ壊して
let's break through them!
吸い込まれそうな保存
Looking up at the night sky...保存
夜空を見上げて
...that seems to swallow me whole,
今 叫ぶよ スターライト
I scream out now, starlight!
I wanna be
そう 僕らは
Yes, we...
いつでも 側で笑い合って
...will always laugh together by each other's side.
あふれる声が 遠くこだまする
Our overflowing voices echo far and wide,
願いの かけらを
carrying the fragments of our wishes...
もしも君の腕を引いて
If I were to take your hand...
どこへだって きらり
and go anywhere, sparkling...
飛んでゆけるんだ
...I can fly!
ちょっと不安な日も
Even on days full of worry,
魔法をかけてハッピー
I'll cast a spell to make them happy.
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with the strength of a hundred!
アクアブルーに染まる
Dyeing the aqua blue sky,
大空にめがけた
aimed high towards the wide open skies.
鼓動が弾んでいく
My heartbeat begins to race!
We can fly
そう僕らはこの日をずっと待ってたんだ
Yes, we've been waiting for this day all along.
まだ醒めないで スターライト
Please don't wake up yet, Starlight!
僕らは止まらない
We won't stop.
その光が消える
Until that light fades,
1秒前まで走り続けるよ
I will keep running until the very last second!
無限の宇宙に響いた
Echoing across the infinite universe,
キミを照らす声を
the voice that shines upon you,
強く抱いて きらり
hold it tight, sparkling,
輝いてゆけ！
and shine on!
いつだって愛情が先に
Love is always the first to...
走り出す 僕らのランウェイを
...start running down our runway.
頑丈とラッキーを盾に
With resilience and luck as our shield,
進まれます Are you ready?
we advance. Are you ready?
転んだって泣いたって僕ら
Even if we fall or cry,
慣れてるよ 受け身はパーフェクト
we're used to it. Our landing is perfect!
笑ってくれてありがとう また僕は歌えるよ
Thank you for smiling. Now I can sing again.
人生は不安ばっか
Life is full of anxieties,
正直自信はないけど
and honestly, I lack confidence...
君の隣だけは譲る気はないのです！
...but the spot right next to you is one thing I'll never give up!
僕らが出会えた
In this miraculous world
奇跡のセカイ
where we were able to meet,
君の目にどう映るかな
I wonder how it looks in your eyes?
青より澄み渡る
It's clearer than any blue,
僕だけの大空だと言いな
I hope I can call it my very own wide open sky.
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity,
二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
I want to sing of the "now" we spend together.
この惑星の片隅続く
Continuing in a corner of this planet,
あいまいみーゆえに
because of our ambiguity...
ラブミ！
...love me!
ナンセンスな現実が
When nonsensical realities
心を乱していった
begin to cloud my mind,
ラッキーの天秤の裏側にある
on the other side of the scales of luck...
アンラッキー
...lies bad luck.
転んだって泣いたって僕ら
Even if we fall or cry,
立ち上がる七転八倒さ
we will stand back up, struggling through life!
笑ってくれてありがとう まだ僕は走れるよ
Thank you for smiling. Now I can keep running.
人生の期待感は
The expectations of life
正直膨らむばっかでさ
honestly just keep on growing,
君の心の中 灯るひだまりなのです
becoming a sunny spot lit up inside your heart.
僕らが暮らしてる
In this miraculous era
奇跡の時代
that we are living in,
君のことどう照らすかな
I wonder how I can shine upon you?
星より煌めいた
Shining brighter than any star,
僕らしい太陽になれたら
if only I could become a sun like myself.
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity,
二人で過ごす今を楽しんでいたい
I want to enjoy the "now" we spend together.
この惑星の片隅続く
Continuing in a corner of this planet,
あいまいみーゆえに楽しんで
because of our ambiguity, let's enjoy it!
今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for today!
ここまで活動できたのは応援してくれたみんなのおかげです！
Being able to do this for so long is all thanks to everyone's support!
いつも本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much as always!
みんな、大好きだぞー！
I love you all!
健やかなる時も
In sickness and in health,
病める時もきっと
and through any difficult times,
伝えたいよこのメロディ
I surely want to convey this melody to you.
僕らが出会えた
In this miraculous world
奇跡のセカイ
where we were able to meet,
君の目にどう映るかな
I wonder how it looks in your eyes?
青より澄み渡る
It's clearer than any blue,
僕だけの大空だと言いな
I hope I can call it my very own wide open sky.
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity,
二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
I want to sing of the "now" we spend together.
この惑星の片隅続く
Continuing in a corner of this planet,
あいまいみーゆえに
because of our ambiguity...
ラブミ！
...love me!
アイラブユー伝えたいの
I want to tell you "I love you"!
これからも、楽しい事いっぱい一緒にやろうね！
Let's keep doing lots of fun things together!